

Full stack developer /Team lead 10+ years experienced.

Germany, Düsseldorf 40217 Babak.zarrinbal@gmail.com

+49 157 3489 7539

ABOUT ME

I'm a 10+ years experienced Full stack developer / Team Lead with vast skill set in developing, mentoring developers, create and leading teams, architecting, and managing small and huge Projects in different fields from commercial to Telecom domain.

My expertise extends to creating and maintaining microservices, all-encompassing

<u>LinkedIn:</u>

https://linkedin.com/in/babak-zarrinbal/

NPM:

https://npmjs.com/~babak.zarrinbal

GitHub:

https://github.com/babakzarrinbal

GitLab:

https://gitlab.com/bzarrinbal

applications, and pioneering prototypes, along with their front-end and back-end frameworks. I've tackled intricate algorithms to guarantee product reliability and efficiency. My ability to simplify complex query procedures enhances performance, while rapid prototyping facilitates efficient analysis and oversight.

Known for my sharp intellect, resourcefulness, and vibrant energy, I thrive as a collaborative team player. My philosophy of continuous self-learning drives my growth, and I believe in taking initiative rather than waiting to be taught.

EXPERIENCE AND EXPERTISE:

TECHNOLOGIES

Architecture

Micro-service, Micro-Frontend, CI/CD, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Docker, Rancher, Oracle cloud, Azure cloud, Google cloud.

Platforms

Linux Backend apps, Web Apps, Electron, React Native, chrome extensions, vocode extensions

Languages

JavaScript (my main and current stack), PHP (haven't worked with in a long time), JAVA (Debugged only)

Database

Oracle DB, Mongo dB, Cassandra DB, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQL Server

Message Brokers

RabbitMQ, Kafka, MQTT

Frameworks

TypeScript, NestJs, GraphQL, ReactJS, NextJS, VueJS, Angular, AngularJS, React Native, ElectronJS, ExpressJS, FastifyJS, SocketIO, SailsJS, Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Sass, Less, Laravel, Drupal, symphony, and lots and lots of side framework for NodeJS, React, Vue and Angular, Laravel and Drupal

Management

Grafana, Kibana, GitHub Reporting, Jira, Kanban Boards, Teams, Excel, MS Projects, Grant graphs, and a lot of meeting with talented people

Tools

MOST RECENT CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Since Feb 2022: Fueling Innovation at Retraced: I'm currently spearheading teams at Retraced, an international trailblazer in tracing and sustainability. As a Team Lead, I'm driving groundbreaking solutions that impact global processes. From Node.js services to Oracle databases, I orchestrate diverse technologies to achieve remarkable results.

2018 - 2022 Tecnotree: Where Innovation Meets Telecom Navigating the intricate landscape of international telecommunications at Tecnotree, I spearheaded a 20-member strong team as a Technical Lead. In this Finnish software powerhouse, I not only pioneered the development of applications that underpin crucial telecom operations but also mentored and guided teams to resounding success. From orchestrating Node.js marvels to seamlessly managing Kubernetes, I ensured our services remained at the forefront of innovation.

From **2012** On Ecommerce, Geolocation, Education: My journey began in the dynamic realms of Ecommerce, Geolocation, and Education. In these diverse sectors, I crafted versatile solutions and pioneered novel approaches. My leadership style has empowered teams, driving excellence in performance, and fostering innovation.

EDUCATIONS AND SKILLS

- University: B.A. of Industrial Eng. from University of science and culture (Tehran, Iran)
- Languages:
 - English (Fluent) has been working with international teams since 2008.
 - Persian (Native), my mother tongue
 - German (A2), in process of learning
 - Arabic (basic understanding)
- Project management courses for MBA
- financial management courses
- Project planning and control courses

Work History

Retraced: (since Feb 2022)

As a hands-on **technical manager/team lead** I teach, guide, and work alongside my teammates to reach the goals of the platform which is vary.

technologies included:

- NodeJS micro services
- React front-end app
- Circle ci / github flows
- Watchdog for production monitoring
- Oracle db
- RabbitMQ
- Docker, Kubernetes, Github Actions

Tecnotree: (Sep 2018-Feb 2022)

As a **Technical Manager** I've managed 3 teams regarding development and maintenance of multiple (more then 70) services to ensure delivery of 3 main telecommunication projects in here I've managed, created, educated and guided new teams, and implemented the one man do it all approach on all the scenarios and proud to say I have guided almost 10+ people from junior seniority skills Technologies included:

- Nodejs
- Spring boot
- Cassandra, mongo dB, MySQL,
- Kafka, RabbitMQ
- Rancher, docker, Kubernetes
- React, Vue, AngularJS.
- Ci/cd with Jenkins

Diliviri/Eposense: (Sep 2017-Sep 2018)

As **Team Lead and senior full stack** developer I developed and improved existing parts of the whole ecosystem of the Diliviri (app for deliver goods with hired/outsourced driver and vehicles). I added multiple apps as well as improvement in followings ...

- Changed monolithic Admin app to microservice architect (Efficiency +400%)
- Converted Driver & Supervisor Native apps for IOS, Android to PWA apps (Development costs -60%)
- Created complex Multi routing algorithms for concurrent deliveries with one driver (profit avg +50%)
- Kick started standalone routing (in map) and tile Api server for completely free of charge map view and routing (map costs -100%)
- Created CI/CD procedure to ensure code health and faster integration for testing and deployment (DevUp costs 70%)
- Creating/modifying and managing 6 apps under the whole product ...

Rahpooyan: (Mar 2014-Sep 2017)

As **full stack** developer I developed and kickstarted and multiple products based on multiple customer needs and descriptions.

- Easybimeh.com (front-end) Improving system for example adding lazy loading and breaking services for better user experience (Efficiency +40%)
- Wow.kanoon.ir (full stack) create and deploy full featured learning app to teach/test and give certificate for English learning (Creating revenue)
- Visit24.ir (full stack) create and deploy 4 different parts whole startup to kickstart it and created the development team and mentored them to continue the work (Creating revenue)
- Review (full stack) creation and deployment of video clip audio extraction and translation plus online subtitle creation (Creating revenue)
- Choqok (full stack) creation and deployment of pdf modification and content adding system for teachers/ reviewers/ experts/ students (Creating revenue)
- Multiple Crawlers for extracting information from different sites and Api for creating datasets and using them in different projects. (Creating revenue)
- Apanajh (front-end) creating front end for Apanajh social media startup and create and mentor front-end team for them ... (Creating revenue)
- Multiple sites and application for various use cases

• Freelance Jobs /ISIRAN: (2013 to 2014)

A Lot of front-end / full-stack project that I've done in that period mainly done with php/Laravel MySQL and VueJs AngularJs and some with Drupal, and after a while I got hired in ISIRAN and this was my first full time development job

Atlas-Offshore, Knauf Iran: (2008 to 2013)

I worked as project planner / controller in mostly gas and oil projects , sometimes as team managers and leaders. I Developed a lot of features and mini apps to perform their tasks and automate them , at some point I developed a whole reporting system that decreased the cost of procedure and man/hour about 50%